# Nathalie Ivette Mc Dermott Junior Full Stack Developer

lvettedemcdermott@gmail.com 089 429 27 26 Co. Clare https://ivettemcdermott.github.io/BasicPortfolio/ ww.linkedin.com/in/ivette-mc-dermott/ github.com/lvetteMcDermott

- Currently enrolled in the National College of Ireland, pursuing a Higher Diploma in Science in Computing, specializing in Software Development.
- Graduate from Code Institute with a diploma in Full Stack Software Development.
- 17 years experience in an administrative role which involved customer service.
- Enjoy exchange of ideas sessions, effective communication skills and ability to solve problems.
- Looking forward to joining an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute, eager about coding, and learn new technologies.
- Resident of Ireland for over 3 years, with Stamp 4 and available to work within short notice.
- Native Spanish speaker and fluid advance English.

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Science in Computing 2024

National College of Ireland - Ireland

Full Stack Developer 2023

Code Institute - Ireland

• English 1998

Instituto de Idiomas de la Universidad Católica Lima, Perú

### **SKILLS**

#### **Soft Skills**

Problem solving, adaptability, communication, interpersonal skills. Enjoy of work with a team, where ideas can be exchange and knowledge grow.

Cohort Lead, CI Course (October '22 - May '23):

- Organized and led weekly sessions to support student learning and motivation, ensuring continuity and resilience during challenges.
- Facilitated collaborative group projects to share skills acquired from various groups with the cohort, promoting effective teamwork and practical application of course concepts.

Class Representative, NCI (Jan - Jun 2024):

• Acted as a bridge between NCI administration and classmates, enhancing communication and addressing student concerns to improve the overall student experience.

# **Developer Skills**

Being the Diploma a bootcamp, the skills were to be learn at a fast pace to a level so that they could be applied in the projects to submit. After it I took small workshops and courses to maintain and improve and expand my

skills.

Experienced through institute learning in the following technologies:

Languages and Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Flask, Django, Java.

Database: PostgreSQL (Elephant), SQL, Firebase.

Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap.

IDE: Gitpod, CodeAnywhere, PyCharm, VsCode.

Hosts: Github for repositories. And for deployment GitHub, Vercel and Heroku.

Agile: GitHub Project Board

Others: Stripe, EmailJs, API implementations.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### November 2020 to Present

Helping the family to transition and taking care of household. On 2022, I went back to study with CI course with the goal to get prepared to return to work. And more recently, this 2024, took the course Certificate in Science in Computing at NCI and now enrolled in the Higher Diploma.

30 October 2020 Moved to Ireland with Spouse Visa.

English Teacher – Introduction to English Nido – Kindergarten "La Semillita" 2018 - 2020 English Teacher – Introduction to English Nido "Kanguru" 2019 - 2019

- Having sessions to introduce the English language to children between 3 to 5 years old.
- Sessions were run in base to a lesson plan for 30 minutes each.
- Ensure that there were activities depending on the age of the group.

## October 2016 – February 2018 Lima, Perú

• Was made redundant due to closure of business on 2016, and decided to spend a year with my infant son.

Secretary/Manager Assistant 2000 - 2016 Clínica Psiquiátrica María Auxiliadora Lima, Perú

- Provide clients with information according to the doctor's order and sign the contracts for these.
- Supervise and coordinate where needed in medical services for the client.
- Generate, keep track, and collect bills from the clients. Service capacity of 55 clients.
- Management of the work schedule for employees and workers in the service and for special requests.
- Generate and manage the payroll. Employees 12 and workers by shift 25.
- Keep control of the stock of materials in each area and supply according to necessity.
- Handling client's complaints or enquiries, resolving the issues and sending reports where necessary.

Management Counter 1999 Instituto Peruano de la Visión Lima, Perú

- Generate, keep track, and collect bills from the clients, private and insurance companies.
- Coordination between services.
- Handling client's' complaints or enquiries, resolving the issues.

Manual Tester Free lancer 1996 - 1998 Third Party Agents Lima, Perú

# **INTERESTS**

• Participate in different communities where can follow and attend workshops, also get involved in collaborative projects.